<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gilles Bertaux : Co-founder/CEO Livestorm</title>
    <description>My name is Gilles Bertaux. I am the co-founder and CEO of Livestorm. Striving to make webinars smarter. Formerly Product Designer at TOTEMS and Growth at Mention.</description>
    <link>http://gillesbertaux.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://gillesbertaux.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 17:09:52 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 17:09:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Imgurians be like</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;one-of-us&quot;&gt;One of us&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using Imgur for almost a year now. I did not use to spend time on Imgur or 9gag or whatever before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder sometimes what the hell I used to do with my time before Imgur. But I can’t help telling myself that I should have started sooner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/EjE0lFX.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur browsing&quot; title=&quot;Imgur browsing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t post often, and, unlike on HN or Designer News, I’m not running after karma. But, unlike HN or Designer News, I can keep browsing the feed for hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do I find in this? It’s hard to say. Confort? What problem is Imgur solving for me? None. And, hell, I don’t mind. I guess it’s ok to have that one app you can go to shamelessly procrastinate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a different matter, I find fascinating how they built this “home” for their community. I think Imgur is way more than just a simple image sharing platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an outsider, it seems sometimes as if the platform was an entire private joke between its members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They really created a place for a community with its own norms, figures and language to emerge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, similar products managed to become such community-driven platforms. 9gag, 4chan or Reddit also have their respective culture. Still, I’m not sure there’s a lot of places that combines this amount of people and such strong culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best example of this appropriation is when you read the never ending debates on whether X or Y is better. I don’t have a decided opinion on this matter. I guess everyone can relate to certain characteristics within a group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, after a year of browsing Imgur I managed to gather 30 reasons why I love it so much. Also, there’s a lot of references in there, so if you get them then you’re probably one of us ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;imgurians-be-like&quot;&gt;Imgurians be like&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I will never see science the same&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mondays are awesome&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/user/ANewBadlyPhotoshoppedPhotoofMichaelCeraEveryday/submitted&quot;&gt;Usernames matter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s not just images. It’s also comments, titles, usernames…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/sEsyOkC&quot;&gt;Reactions I can relate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Faith restored in Internet comments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/a/ViEfT&quot;&gt;I found myself a thing for slow-motioned, smooth, industrial processes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;@sarah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/a/QagTv&quot;&gt;The proof that cats are jerks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/a/Yg8hB&quot;&gt;And the pr-woof that dogs are awesome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/a/HSgVG&quot;&gt;I now have a name for those. “Nopes”.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[Insert talking animal here] - [Animal], probably&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/a/m1ahl&quot;&gt;All the fav-and-forgets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/a/pySQf&quot;&gt;Tough guy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/PpwifrF&quot;&gt;Samuel L. Jackson of dogs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/oVFKAd1&quot;&gt;U wot m8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/HeuNfVl&quot;&gt;Moon moon jokes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/a/tD4Gp&quot;&gt;Space pictures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/4kLvWOd&quot;&gt;Fatness everywhere&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/rTD43Nj&quot;&gt;Nature&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/l2yRA1E&quot;&gt;Cosplayers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/LfDZSHA&quot;&gt;Strong, heavy intellectual, brainstorming sessions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/a/dmJ0J&quot;&gt;Adventures of imgurians&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://imgur.com/wBtPCiN&quot;&gt;Imma touch tha fishy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/gallery/43oKh79&quot;&gt;Arms make everything better&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/orgzsd9&quot;&gt;I found out that I have a problem with closure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/gallery/rP3mKq1&quot;&gt;Shh, no tears…Only dreams now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/gdrz2QK&quot;&gt;Trash-pandas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/a/ttHGm&quot;&gt;Oh right the murders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/5u2DrMx&quot;&gt;Travolta everywhere&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/a/DChSg&quot;&gt;Imgurian’s wives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/RoUT76A&quot;&gt;Cats are liquid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/T7ghiT8&quot;&gt;Glorious text conversations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Politecat tax&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/Jy4TM1w.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Polite cat&quot; title=&quot;polite cat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gillesbertaux.com/blog/imgurians-be-like/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gillesbertaux.com/blog/imgurians-be-like/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hacking the Twitter Follow Button: Mass Follow Shortcut</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s a little trick I found playing around with Twitter the other day. I had this Twitter list full of relevant people for &lt;a href=&quot;https://rumble.live&quot;&gt;Rumble&lt;/a&gt;, it had hundreds of profiles. I could follow them one by one but that would have taken forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did one simple thing: &lt;strong&gt;I retrieved the CSS selector path of a “Follow” button (making sure to exclude the “Unfollow”), and triggered a quick JQuery&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.click()&lt;/code&gt; &lt;strong&gt;method to click on all the matching elements&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/follow-script.gif&quot; alt=&quot;script gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/gillesbertaux/7a4ec47a73f3d8b047a12f4d1ed04bb1.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was already pretty useful, but I wanted something more straightforward than having to open the console and paste the snippet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what I came up with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;padding: 10px 20px;     background: #059FF5;     border-radius: 3px;     margin: 10px 0;     display: inline-block;     font-weight: 600;     color: #fff;&quot; href=&quot;javascript:$(&#39;div.user-actions.btn-group.not-following.not-muting &amp;gt; button&#39;).slice(0,50).click()&quot;&gt;Mass Twitter Follow Button&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just drag this button in your bookmark bar and here you go : &lt;strong&gt;a mass follow button&lt;/strong&gt;. Just hit that button and you will trigger a click on 50 follow buttons in your window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/button.gif&quot; alt=&quot;button gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This actually gave me the following idea: it’d be awesome to have &lt;strong&gt;a small library of shortcuts to trigger very simple scripts&lt;/strong&gt;. It could help marketers, or people who just don’t code, solving simple problems, gain time and, at the end of the day, be more productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope that helps.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gillesbertaux.com/blog/mass-follow-shortcut/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gillesbertaux.com/blog/mass-follow-shortcut/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Food Recommendation Slack Bot with Zapier</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using Zapier intensively for a while now and I built some pretty advanced cool integrations with all sort of tools. Most of them were business related but I wanted to show you how we hacked some fun stuff for our own offices at &lt;a href=&quot;https://livestorm.co&quot;&gt;Livestorm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the basic story I was aiming for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Every day at noon, I pick a random item in a pre-built restaurant DB. Then the Slack bot sends a new message in our #notifications channel containing the restaurant info.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the main steps to build the Slack Bot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scrap a viable source of restaurants&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clean the data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start the Zapier integration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Insert a small JS script to randomize&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Send the message in Slack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;find-a-reliable-source-of-data&quot;&gt;Find a reliable source of data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First things first, let’s find some data source worth scrapping. I figured that Yelp was our best choice but you might have some local platform in your area that’s more accurate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want restaurants with the following criterias:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delivery service (Not every restaurant in France offers that service…)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Good restaurants&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reasonably cheap&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Close to the office&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open at noon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to Yelp and applied those criterias. Then copy paste the URL once the criterias are applied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/yelp.png&quot; alt=&quot;yelp-criterias&quot; title=&quot;yelp screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;crawl-the-source-using-importiohttpimportio--store-in-google-spreadsheet&quot;&gt;Crawl the source using &lt;a href=&quot;http://import.io&quot;&gt;Import.io&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; Store in Google Spreadsheet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not going to do a step by step tutorial on Import.io since it’s pretty straightfroward. Basically, pick the Crawler option and then go to your Yelp URL. Each data type will be a column in the final CSV generated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pick the data you need, here I selected:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Title&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pricing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Type&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rating&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Address&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phone number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/importio.png&quot; alt=&quot;import.io&quot; title=&quot;import.io screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it! Then just run the crawler. Now import the whole thing to Google Spreadsheet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/sheet.png&quot; alt=&quot;spreadsheet data&quot; title=&quot;spreadsheet data&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I over used the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;=REGEXEXTRACT()&lt;/code&gt; formula to clean it. Make sure you have the HTML of each item in a column in the list so that you can extract every element you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-zapier-integration&quot;&gt;The Zapier integration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost there. First, since we want the script to run every day at noon, we’ll start with the Sheduling built-in app from Zapier:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/schedule.png&quot; alt=&quot;schedule zapier&quot; title=&quot;schedule zapier&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s insert a small Javascript snippet to trigger a random number. Here we trigger something between 1 and 331 because I have 331 entries in my database:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/zapier-js.png&quot; alt=&quot;javascript zapier&quot; title=&quot;javascript zapier&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we link our spreadshseet. We want to look up for that random value, we will be reusing the matching row’s data later:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/zapier-lookup-sheet.png&quot; alt=&quot;lookup sheet zapier&quot; title=&quot;lookup sheet zapier&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Final touch, we create our Slack message:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/slack-zapier.png&quot; alt=&quot;slack zapier&quot; title=&quot;slack zapier&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And voilà. Here’s how it looks every day at noon:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/slack-msg.png&quot; alt=&quot;slack message&quot; title=&quot;slack message&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be 100% honest we stopped using it at &lt;a href=&quot;https://livestorm.co&quot;&gt;Livestorm&lt;/a&gt; because the data we scraped was not as reliable as we thought. So try to get some real good up to date data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next step will be: cleaner data and a basic hosted randomization engine server-side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope that helps.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gillesbertaux.com/blog/food-slack-bot-zapier/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gillesbertaux.com/blog/food-slack-bot-zapier/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SaaS Marketing Startup Stack #1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I just wanted to list of all the SaaS tools I would love to use if my resources were limitless. This is the first version. I’ll make another list as my usage evolves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first part of several posts in which you’ll find a variety of tools in every field whereas it is marketing, tech, design or even operations (HR, admin, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the marketing stack, that’s an easy one. During my last year at Mention I learned to use almost a dozen of marketing tools, and maybe tested twice as many, so I have pretty good idea of what tools could fit my needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-data-collection-segment&quot;&gt;For data collection: Segment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I discovered &lt;a href=&quot;//segment.com&quot;&gt;Segment&lt;/a&gt; with Mention and I will probably bring it with me everywhere I go from now on. Segment is just incredibly powerful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Briefly, Segment is a « data hub », a unified API fr tracking. It provides an API to push front-end or server-side standardized events from your app to Segment and then to any software that has a Segment integration (+100 integrations).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you send an « Upgrade » event to Segment, you’ll be able to find it on your analytics tool, emailing software, CRM or even Twitter Ads, Facebook Conversions or Google Adwords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One tool to find them, One tool to track them all and in the darkness bind them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/segment.png&quot; alt=&quot;Segment&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-analyticsbi-amplitude&quot;&gt;For analytics/BI: Amplitude&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tested some analytics tools outside of the good ol’ Google Analytics and the one I enjoyed the most was &lt;a href=&quot;//amplitude.com&quot;&gt;Amplitude&lt;/a&gt;. It provides cool features such as funnels, events segmentation, user search, custom dashboards and the ability to cross your data with user properties. It even allows SQL commands on your data (only available for big ass premium plans).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other cool options are &lt;a href=&quot;//kissmetrics.com&quot;&gt;Kissmetrics&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;//mixpanel.com&quot;&gt;Mixpanel&lt;/a&gt; . It is very reliable with Segment, awesome power reports, but the learning curve is a bit high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/amplitude.png&quot; alt=&quot;Amplitude&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The real-time map of events in Amplitude&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-mailing-customerio&quot;&gt;For mailing: Customer.io&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By mailing I distinguish two things: automatic nurturing/transactional emails and blog newsletters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met &lt;a href=&quot;//customer.io&quot;&gt;Customer.io&lt;/a&gt; two years ago and I would never change for any other solution now. Customer.io is to me the best emailing solution out there because of its customization capability. Because of its &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Shopify/liquid/wiki/Liquid-for-Designers&quot;&gt;Liquid&lt;/a&gt; syntax inside the emails templates you can so awesome stuff like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;{ if customer.plan_value.size &amp;gt; 0 and customer.plan_value &amp;gt; 200 % and customer.app_rating &amp;lt; 6 }
Hello !&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;My name is , I am your account manager on your  plan. I saw that yesterday you gave us a rating of , I am terribly sorry you had such a bad experience. What were your pain points? Can we make a one-on-one Skype so that you can show me what is wrong ? I will do my best to help you.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Have a great day,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;{ else }
{ endif }&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it has a Segment integration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-crm--customer-success-depends&quot;&gt;For CRM &amp;amp; Customer Success: Depends…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, here I’m not really sure. I believe there is a CRM for every stage of a company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, an early-stage startup will be satisfied with a basic Streak gmail add-on or &lt;a href=&quot;//frontapp.com&quot;&gt;Front&lt;/a&gt; (not a CRM tool I know) for both sales and CS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then maybe switching sales to &lt;a href=&quot;//close.io&quot;&gt;Close.io&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;//pipedrive.com&quot;&gt;Pipedrive&lt;/a&gt; would be a good idea. Finally once you reached a certain size and struggle with hundreds of leads you’ll want to switch your sales team to Salesforce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for CS, once you have a proper CS team, moving to simple tools such as &lt;a href=&quot;//zendesk.com&quot;&gt;Zendesk&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;//totango.com&quot;&gt;Totango&lt;/a&gt; (Segment integrations \o/).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To sum up:
- Early stage: Streak + Front
- Startup: Close.io + Zendesk
- Company: Salesforce&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-live-chat-chatlio&quot;&gt;For live chat: Chatlio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not very well known, this small startup has an awesome team and their product is top notch. &lt;a href=&quot;//chatlio.com&quot;&gt;Chatlio&lt;/a&gt; is the only live chat tool that integrates directly with Slack. So basically, you get a new cool chat without leaving the one you already use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could get easily messy, but in the end everything work like a charm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-analyzing-user-behaviors-fullstory&quot;&gt;For analyzing user behaviors: Fullstory&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//fullstory.com&quot;&gt;Fullstory&lt;/a&gt; « records » every single users on your app and even keep track of the logs in the console. It means that you can bring the popcorn, sit back, and watch your users struggling with your brand new signup form. As they say: it’s a DVR for your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is indeed very useful to get full insights on why X users are behaving this way or why did they get a form error. Fullstory could be useful not just marketers but also for product managers or even UX designers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here it is, I might be updating this post a little bit with SEO tools such as Moz or BI/Dashboard softwares. Let me know what you think in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gillesbertaux.com/blog/my-startup-dream-stack-marketing-tools/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gillesbertaux.com/blog/my-startup-dream-stack-marketing-tools/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tubelist.co: from MVP to ProductHunt launch in 14 days</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Personnaly I spend way more time watching Youtube on my AppleTV than watching TV. Not only Youtube brought tailored, customized content to everyone but it has also incentivated like never before content creation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, unlike traditional media (TV industry and movie industry included), we, as users, do not have a good way to explore, discover content and get inspired on Youtube… outside of Youtube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where Tubelist comes in. TubeList is a new way to explore and discover new Youtube channels everyday and upvote the ones you like. Think of it as a Product Hunt or a Reddit for Youtube channels. TubeList is also a cool way for youtubers to promote their channel, get more views and create more amazing content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tubelist is a side-project we launched with my teammate Vincent Garreau.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/tubelist-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;tubelist home&quot; title=&quot;tubelist home&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;have-a-hackerproduct-fit&quot;&gt;1. Have a hacker/product fit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thought that it would be cool to have something we could use ourselves: a very simple tool to explore Youtube and get new content everyday. It was not hard to find people with the same needs, often on Twitter people were asking for channel suggestions to their followers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, since Reddit, Product Hunt, or Hacker News were part of our daily curation routine, it seemed like the simplest way to present it that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may sound silly or obvious, but having a real enthusiasm for the product we were building really boosted our productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/tubelist-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;tubelist channel&quot; title=&quot;tubelist channel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-out-of-the-building&quot;&gt;2. “Get out of the building”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily enough we knew three Youtubers, with very different profiles. Lucie Zevaco (@mezlulu) vlogs on beauty/fashion/lifestyle, Julien Dachaud (@newtiteuf) makes videos on Pokemon games and Thomas Iturralde (@Laink) produces awesome gaming/comedy videos. We reached out to those three in order to iterate more efficiently on our idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/tubelist-4.png&quot; alt=&quot;tubelist channel bottom&quot; title=&quot;tubelist channel bottom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;have-a-modular-approach&quot;&gt;3. Have a modular approach&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We relied on flexible yet strong technologies that could provide everything we wanted in no time with a minimal learning curve. This is why, after some hesitation with Rails, we eventually built TubeList architecture with basic PHP/MySQL and Kirby, a flat-file CMS, which provided just the flexibility we needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, to organize things, we basically listed all the features we wanted, translated them in user stories and splitted them in three modules “core features”, “release version”, “backlog”. This modular approach would drive our whole development process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This very first iteration had minimal identity and CSS, we would take care of design later. Our concern was to have something functional. After the first week of development we had pretty much everything we wanted in terms of functionalities, it was time to get to the fun stuff : design and branding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than make pixel-perfect mockups, which is very consuming in time, we had the same modular approach for design. We decomposed our project in UI elements and crafted a UI kit directly in Sketch during the following week-end. This decision was also influenced by the fact it would be easier then to translate those UI elements in SASS and HTML components and then develop faster reusing those modules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, in case you wonder, we mostly worked on remote through Slack, Trello and very few Google Documents to keep things very simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;automate-development-and-growth&quot;&gt;4. Automate development and growth.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to ship fast and keep a strong focus on our product, we had to find ways to easily automate our process as much as we could without building complex environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, to ship code faster, we used a  Github + FTploy integration in which every push to the Master branch is a push to our FTP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, to keep our partners informed on our progress, rather than sending emails everyday and spend hours in our inbox, we invited them to our Slack channel. Then we integrated our Trello changes + Github notifications with a public Slack channel called #notifications. That way people could track the progress in real time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concerning growth and content creation, we made a great use of Zapier, Google Spreadsheets, Kimono and the Augur.io API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create a DB of Youtubers to reach, we scraped SocialBlade Tops 500 with Kimono to get the Youtube channels IDs present in SocialBlade URLs, built new URLs pointing to their Youtube channels and import them to a spreadsheet. Then we visited every channel to see if there was a business email in their about section. We stopped at 100 leads. Now we are currently using Amazon Mechanical Turk to do that for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there it is, we hope you found it interesting! If you have any comment, any idea on how we could improve this process, leave us a comment we would love to hear it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/tubelist-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;tubelist about&quot; title=&quot;tubelist about&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, we would like to thank the people who participated to this project: our friends, family and colleagues of course, but also Lucie Zevaco, Julien Dachaud, Thomas Iturralde, and thanks to Product Hunt and especially Ryan who agreed to highlight TubeList on Product Hunt, you are amazing!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gillesbertaux.com/blog/tubelist-case-study/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gillesbertaux.com/blog/tubelist-case-study/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Startup HR: Chief Culture Officer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s an idea I had the other day after watching &lt;a href=&quot;http://startupclass.samaltman.com/&quot;&gt;“Hiring and Culture”&lt;/a&gt; from the startup class series. Here’s what could be a job offer for a Chief Culture Officer. His job would be to help the CEO maintain and coordinate the culture attributes of a company. Such position would probably be relevant only after reaching a certain size and maturity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;responsabilites&quot;&gt;Responsabilites&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coordinating a vision and core values can be really challenging once you have reached a certain size and maturity. Keeping the message clear and unaltered for every employee, recruit or candidate is a long-term undertaking. You will be in charge of building strategies and lead actions to keep that message loud and clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lead and coordinate the HR departement and the marketing department to elaborate “culture strategies”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure that every interaction from the employees are marked with the company’s DNA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;requirements&quot;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deeply understand and integrate the history, core values and principles of the company.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have constantly an empathic and psychological approach to understand any context or subject.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creativity to elaborate new ways of promoting the company’s culture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leadership to coordinate departments, teams and people from different backgrounds and make them converge to one single objective.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have range, be comfortable around different backgrounds to understand how they receive and apply the company’s culture into their daily activity.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Great communication and social skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know what you think about having a CCO and its role. Also, do not hesitate to make suggestions for the job requirements, I will be happy to update this post.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gillesbertaux.com/blog/chief-culture-officer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gillesbertaux.com/blog/chief-culture-officer/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
