<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gilles Bertaux : Product Design + Growth</title>
    <description>Hi there, my name is Gilles Bertaux. Formerly Product Designer at TOTEMS, now Growth at Mention. I do: Product Management, Product Design &amp; Growth.</description>
    <link>http://gillesbertaux.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://gillesbertaux.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 16:11:30 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 16:11:30 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Startup HR: Chief Culture Officer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s an idea I had the other day after watching &lt;a href=&quot;http://startupclass.samaltman.com/&quot;&gt;“Hiring and Culture”&lt;/a&gt; from the startup class series. Here’s what could be a job offer for a Chief Culture Officer. His job would be to help the CEO maintain and coordinate the culture attributes of a company. Such position would probably be relevant only after reaching a certain size and maturity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;responsabilites&quot;&gt;Responsabilites&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coordinating a vision and core values can be really challenging once you have reached a certain size and maturity. Keeping the message clear and unaltered for every employee, recruit or candidate is a long-term undertaking. You will be in charge of building strategies and lead actions to keep that message loud and clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lead and coordinate the HR departement and the marketing department to elaborate “culture strategies”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure that every interaction from the employees are marked with the company’s DNA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;requirements&quot;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deeply understand and integrate the history, core values and principles of the company.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have constantly an empathic and psychological approach to understand any context or subject.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creativity to elaborate new ways of promoting the company’s culture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leadership to coordinate departments, teams and people from different backgrounds and make them converge to one single objective.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have range, be comfortable around different backgrounds to understand how they receive and apply the company’s culture into their daily activity.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Great communication and social skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know what you think about having a CCO and its role. Also, do not hesitate to make suggestions for the job requirements, I will be happy to update this post.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://gillesbertaux.com/blog/chief-culture-officer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gillesbertaux.com/blog/chief-culture-officer/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Prevent Gmail App From Autoscaling HTML Emails</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Emails clients are terrible at doing their job. Especially Gmail and, obviously Outlook. Recently, I had this very frustrating experience: we had a HTML emails, optimized for desktop email clients BUT the Gmail app on iOS and Android were autoscaling the typography by 50% breaking the whole layout. After some research, I finally found a hack to solve this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But let me first list all of the potential solutions that I tried. Maybe those will fix your problem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add a table row width a single cell set to your email width.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add  &lt;em&gt;meta name=”viewport” content=”width=device-width, initial-scale=1”&lt;/em&gt; and then set an image (can be a 1px image) that spans the full width of the page.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add add min-width to your background/container table.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add &lt;em&gt;&amp;lt;body style=&quot;-webkit-text-size-adjust:none;&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That might solve your problem on Android. But, for me, at least, the problem was persisting on the Gmail iOS app. Until I found a hack on a blog called &lt;a href=&quot;http://freshinbox.com/blog/gmail-on-ios-increases-font-size-on-some-emails/&quot;&gt;Freshinbox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally here’s the hack, put this code at the bottom of your email above the closing body tag:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div style=&quot;display:none; white-space:nowrap; font:15px courier; color:#ffffff;&quot;&amp;gt;
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the explanation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The white-space:nowrap with the dashed line creates a line about 500px across that when bumped up in size will exceed 700px causing the Gmail app to not apply the font change.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The display:none style causes non-Gmail clients to hide the block (Gmail ignores display:none). When the email is viewed in say, a non-Gmail mobile client, it won’t affect your responsive layout.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The font is set to white so the dashes are not displayed when viewed in Gmail. If you have a different color background, set it to your background color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope this helps ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Btw: I’m working on a template for bootstrapping scalable newsletter optimized for all email clients called Mailstrap, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gillesbertaux/mailstrap&quot;&gt;here’s the github&lt;/a&gt;, you are more than welcome to fork it or leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://gillesbertaux.com/blog/gmail-autoscale-html-emails/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gillesbertaux.com/blog/gmail-autoscale-html-emails/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
